{"test_questions": [[{"question": "When the amino acid alanine (R-group is CH3) is added to a solution with a pH of 7.3, alanine becomes", "opta": "a cation", "optb": "nonpolar", "optc": "a zwitterions", "optd": "an isotope", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the end product of leucine metabolism?", "opta": "Acetyl-CoA", "optb": "Pyruvic acid", "optc": "Oxaloacetic acid", "optd": "Acetyl carnitine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the heaviest of the twenty amino acids?", "opta": "Phenylalanine", "optb": "Tryptophan", "optc": "Tyrosine", "optd": "Histidine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following amino acids can form hydrogen bonds with their side (R) groups?", "opta": "Asparagine", "optb": "Aspartic acid", "optc": "Glutamine", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The isoelectric point of an amino acid is defined as the pH", "opta": "where the molecule carries no electric charge", "optb": "where the carboxyl group is uncharged", "optc": "where the amino group is uncharged", "optd": "of maximum electrolytic mobility", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Molecules that bear charged groups of opposite polarity are known as", "opta": "zwitterions", "optb": "ambions", "optc": "ion conversion", "optd": "amphions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the product of the catabolic breakdown of Arginine?", "opta": "Alpha-ketoglutarate", "optb": "Fumarate", "optc": "Oxaloacetate", "optd": "Succinate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which amino acids would most likely reside in the membrane-anchoring domain of a membrane embedded protein?", "opta": "Isoleucine, valine and phenylalanine", "optb": "Phenylalanine, valine, and aspartate", "optc": "Leucine, threonine, and lysine", "optd": "Lysine, arginine and histidine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An essential amino acid is one that", "opta": "is essentially easy to synthesize", "optb": "is essential to flagella motion", "optc": "the body cannot synthesize", "optd": "the body can synthesize under essential conditions", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "D-Alanine and L-Alanine are technically known as", "opta": "anomers", "optb": "enantiomers", "optc": "epimers", "optd": "polymer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following pairs of amino acids would carry a negative charge on their side chain at pH 8.0?", "opta": "Asparagine & Glutamine", "optb": "Leucine & Glycine", "optc": "Histidine & Lysine", "optd": "Aspartate & Glutamate", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a polypeptide average mass of an amino acid residue is", "opta": "110 daltons", "optb": "118 daltons", "optc": "80 daltons", "optd": "150 daltons", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which pair of amino acids absorbs the most UV light at 280 nm?", "opta": "Threonine & Histidine", "optb": "Trp & Tyrosine", "optc": "Cystein & Asparagine", "optd": "Phenylalnine & Proline", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a nonstandard amino acid?", "opta": "Cysteine", "optb": "Isoleucine", "optc": "Hydroxyproline", "optd": "Histidine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an essential amino acid?", "opta": "Tryptophan", "optb": "Methionine", "optc": "Lysine", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Protein fluorescence arises primarily from which residue?", "opta": "Arginine", "optb": "Tryptophan", "optc": "Tyrosine", "optd": "Phenylalanine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following amino acid is known as half-cystine residue?", "opta": "Cysteine", "optb": "Isoleucine", "optc": "Valine", "optd": "Histidine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an essential amino acid?", "opta": "Aspartic acid", "optb": "Glutamic acid", "optc": "Glycine", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a sensible grouping of amino acids based on their polarity properties?", "opta": "Ala, Leu, and Val", "optb": "Arg, His, and Lys", "optc": "Phe, Trp, and Tyr", "optd": "Asp, Ile, and Pro", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Proteins and macromolecular structures take on their higher order structures", "opta": "by self-assembly", "optb": "with the help of molecular chaperons", "optc": "with the help of precursor sequences that are removed from the final structures", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the product of the catabolic breakdown of Alanine?", "opta": "Fumarate", "optb": "Oxaloacetate", "optc": "Pyruvate", "optd": "Malate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many different amino acids are there?", "opta": "3", "optb": "20", "optc": "100", "optd": "An infinite number", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Amino acids required in the human diet and not synthesized by the body are called", "opta": "specialized", "optb": "trace", "optc": "essential", "optd": "accessory", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following amino acid contain an imidazolium moiety?", "opta": "Alanine", "optb": "Valine", "optc": "Cysteine", "optd": "Histidine", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sequence of letters 'WYQN' will represent", "opta": "Tryptophan, tyrosine, glutamic acid, asparagine", "optb": "Tryptophan, tyrosine, glutamine, asparagine", "optc": "Tryptophan, glutamine, tryptophan, asparagine", "optd": "Glutamine, tyrosine, tryptophan, aspartic acid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sulphur containing side chain of cysteine is", "opta": "ampiphillic, highly reactive and capable of reacting with another cysteine", "optb": "hydrophillc, highly reactive and capable of reacting with another cysteine", "optc": "hydrophobic, highly reactive and capable of reacting with another cysteine", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a nonprotein amino acid?", "opta": "Dopamine", "optb": "Hydroxylysine", "optc": "Cystine", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Serine and threonine are polar amino acids due to", "opta": "reactive hydroxyl group in the side chain", "optb": "reactive alcoholic group in the side chain", "optc": "reactive keto group in the side chain", "optd": "reactive aldehyde group in the side chain", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not the hydrophobic and aromatic amino acid?", "opta": "Phenylalanine", "optb": "Tyrosine", "optc": "Tryptophan", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stereo chemical configuration of all a-amino acids derived from proteins is", "opta": "L", "optb": "D", "optc": "L and D", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The \u03b1-amino acids have a carboxyl group with a pK around __________ , and an amino group with a pK near __________ .", "opta": "1.1, and 12.1", "optb": "6.5, and 8.0", "optc": "3.3, and 10.5", "optd": "2.2, and 9.4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coomassie Blue stains the proteins by reacting with", "opta": "arginine residues", "optb": "free c-termini", "optc": "peptide bonds", "optd": "aromatic ring", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which amino acid when exposed to ninhydrin produces a brown color?", "opta": "Asparagine", "optb": "Proline", "optc": "Alanine", "optd": "Valine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}